Henry Justin Allen Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Post-Gubernatorial File, circa 1923-1942 (Box C1-C137)
  - Campaign File, 1930-1936 (Box C67-C78)
    - Senate, 1930 (Box C67)
      - Confidential (Box C71)
        - Snyder, Ralph
        - Sproul, W.A.
      - Congratulatory letters
      - Contributions
      - Special correspondence
      - Financial statements
      - Grain trade opposition
      - Invitations and engagements
      - Sedgwick County
      - Shawnee County
      - Wyandotte County
      - Legal requirements
      - Lists of workers, Sedgwick County
      - Mailing lists (Box C72)
      - Mailing lists, Cherokee County
      - Newspaper subscriptions
      - Nomination petition
      - Personnel
      - Platforms
      - Polls
      - Publication matters, campaign releases
      - Publications, requests for
        - Publicity
        - Mechanical service
        - Photographs
        - Radio stations
      - Releases, Kansas State Republican Committee
      - Republican National Committee
      - Republican Senatorial Campaign Committee
      - Speakers, suggestions
      - Special correspondence
        - Bailey, C. H.
        - Beezley, George F.
        - Brinkerhoff, Fred
        - Capper, Arthur
        - Clark, George A.
        - Clymer, Rolla
        - Congressional district chairmen
        - Duff, Hugh
        - Edmonds, Leslie (Box C73)
        - Friend, C. E.
        - Getty, James F.
        - Hamilton, John
        - Landon, Alfred M.
        - LeRoy, L. D.
        - McGill, George
        - MacIvor, Donald H.
        - Mercer, J. H.
        - Miller, A. Q.
        - Motter, Harvey H.
        - Reed, Clyde M.
        - Trigg, Fred (Box C74)
        - Underwood, Ernest
        - White, William Allen
      - Surveys
      - Vice-chairmen
        - Shawnee County
        - State Committee
    - National Campaign, 1932 (Box C75)
      - Appointments
      - Campaign speech notes
      - Democrats, clippings
      - Hoover, Herbert, candidacy
      - Hoover, President Herbert,-prohibition
      - Invitations
      - Newspaper prospects, National Daily
      - Newspapers
        - Chicago Evening Post
        - Denver Daily Record Stockman
      - Newspapers for sale, Louisville Herald Post
      - Organization of Southern Drys
      - Prohibition publicity
        - American Businessmen's Prohibition Foundation
        - Miscellaneous
        - Publishers convention
      - Publicity (Box C76)
        - Advertising
        - Speakers
      - Republican National Committee
        - National convention
        - Prohibition
        - Republican platform
      - Ritchie debate
      - Special correspondence
        - Abbot, Willis J.
        - Gannett, Frank E.
        - High, Stanley
        - Hinshaw, David
        - Republican National Committee
        - Richey, Lawrence
    - National Campaign, 1936 (Box C77)
      - Campaign expenses, Allen, Henry J.
      - Democratic Convention
      - Election results
      - Ewing, A.J.
      - Invitations
      - Landon, Alfred M., speech material
      - Landon Fund, (2 folders) (Box C78)
      - Literary Digest poll
      - Notification meeting
      - Polls
      - Publicity
      - Republican convention
      - Republican National Committee, (2 folders)
      - Republican platform
      - Springfield meeting
  - Kansas File (Box C79-C83)
    Correspondence, reports, appointment material, clippings, printed matter, financial matter, and miscellaneous items.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material.
    - Appointments, (2 folders) (Box C79)
      - Assistant business manager
      - Banking Department
      - Barber Board
      - Board of Administration, (2 folders)
      - Board of Health
      - Board of Regents
      - Board of Review
      - Building and Loan Department, (2 folders)
      - Censorship Board
      - Chiropractic Board
      - Fire marshal
      - Game warden
      - Gasoline Tax Department
      - Girls Reform School, Beloit
      - Grain, chief inspector
      - Grain inspection
      - Highway Commission
      - Highway Department
      - Hotel Commission
      - Hutchinson Reformatory
      - Industrial farm
      - Industrial Reformatory
        - Guard
        - Steward
      - Judgeship
      - Justice
      - License inspector
      - Medical examiner, aviators
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - Oil Department
      - Oil inspector
      - Orphans home, Atchison
      - Orphans home, state agent
      - Penitentiary
      - Pharmacy Board
      - Referee in bankruptcy (Box C80)
      - School Book Commission
      - School for deaf, Olathe
      - Soldiers Home, Board of Managers
      - State hospital, (2 folders)
      - State orphans home, steward
      - Tax Commission
      - University of Kansas, Lawrence
      - Vocational School
      - Western University, Quindaro
    - Appointment requests
    - Baker University, Baldwin, (2 folders)
    - Bank tax situation
    - Banking Department
    - Banking matters
    - Building contracts
    - Citizens military training camps
    - Coal mine strike
    - Commonwealth Club
    - Congressional campaign, state and local, 1934
    - County appointments
    - Enrollment of servicemen
    - Federal highways
    - Freight rates
    - Highway Department (Box C81)
    - Historical celebrations
    - Historical society
    - Industrial court, (3 folders)
    - Jurors
    - Kansas Dry Club
    - Kansas road system map
    - Kansas University, Lawrence, (3 folders)
    - Lake project
    - Legislation
      - Intangible tax
      - Oil
    - Legislature, 1939
    - Miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Murals Commission (Box C82)
      - Accounts and collections
      - Curry, John Steuart
      - Dickerson, Mrs. William J.
      - Harris, John P.
      - Miscellaneous
    - Political situation
    - Practice of law
    - Prison matters, (2 folders)
    - Prohibition, (2 folders)
    - Railroad valuation
    - State campaign, 1932 (Box C83)
      - Allen statements
      - Campaign contributions
      - Campaign issues
      - Mailing lists
      - Platforms, other candidates
      - Special correspondence
        - Brinkley, J. R.
        - Carlson, Frank
        - Edmonds, Leslie
        - Hoch, Homer
        - Isely, C. C.
        - Landon, Alfred M.
        - Mercer, J. H.
        - Miller, A. Q.
        - Ward, Cal A.
        - White, William Allen
    - State candidates
    - State campaign, treasurer, 1934
    - State campaign, 1936
      - Governor
      - Miscellaneous
    - State campaign, Clyde Reed, 1941
    - State Hospital parole
    - Taxation
    - Western University, Quindaro
    - Wichita Real Estate Board
  - Legislation File (Box C84-C86)
    Correspondence, reports, and miscellaneous legislative material.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Agricultural Adjustment Act (Box C84)
    - Anti-trust law
    - Cape May, N.J.
    - Chain stores and chain banking
    - China famine relief
    - Communism
    - Copies of acts of Congress
    - Federal Farm Bank law
    - Home Loan Bank bill
    - Illiteracy
    - Liberty Loan bonds
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - National Recovery Act
    - Packers consent decree
    - Philippine independence (Box C85)
    - Post Office legislation
    - Prohibition
    - Radio Act of 1927, amendment
    - Reapportionment
    - Rivers and Harbors bill
    - Road building
    - Russian lumber
    - Tariff
      - French iron trade
      - Milling in bond
      - Miscellaneous
      - Oil (Box C86)
      - Oil, Henry J. Allen's notes
    - Tariff Act, 1930
    - Vestal copyright law
    - Wagner labor law
    - Wheat trade with Holland
    - World Court
    - World War adjusted compensation
  - Near East Relief (Box C87)
    Correspondence, press releases, and miscellaneous material.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
    - Correspondence, (4 folders) (Box C87)
    - News service
    - Personal miscellaneous
  - St. Lawrence Seaway Project (Box C88-C97)
    Correspondence, reports, printed matter, scrapbook, and miscellaneous material.
    - Craig, Charles P., (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box C88, Box C89)
    - Detroit, Mich., meeting, 1936
    - Information file
    - Invitations
    - Laubengayer, R. J., and Roy F. Bailey
    - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous (Box C90)
      - 1921-1922, (2 folders)
      - 1922, (3 folders)
      - 1922 (Box C91)
      - 1927
      - 1929
      - 1929-1930, (2 folders)
      - 1932-1933
      - 1936-1940, (2 folders) (Box C92)
      - Interior Department
      - Wichita
      - Memoranda
      - Printed matter, (2 folders); (6 folders); (5 folders) (Box C93, Box C94, Box C95, Box C96)
    - Morcaux, A. O
    - National Rivers and Harbors Congress
    - Projects Subcommittee
    - Publications
    - Publicity
    - Releases
    - Scrapbook (Box C97)
    - Special file
    - State, Department of
    - Treaty correspondence, (2 folders)
    - Treaty material
  - Save the Children (U.S.) (Box C98-C10)
    Correspondence, reports, press releases, radio scripts, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of person, location, or type of material.
    - California (Box C98)
    - Colorado
    - General
    - London, England
      - Letters
      - Papers
    - Mace, John W. (Box C99)
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders); (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box C100, Box C101)
    - Oklahoma
    - Releases, radio scripts, clippings
    - Solicitation lists, letters and donors
    - Texas
    - Travel matters
    - Voris, John R.
  - Publications File (Box C102-C107)
    Correspondence, articles, clippings, press releases, and printed matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic, organization, location, or type of material.
    - Articles, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box C102, Box C103)
    - Articles, unemployment insurance, (2 folders)
    - Articles for publication
      - Church
      - International Labor News Service
      - Jayhawk
      - Miscellaneous (Box C104)
      - Schools
      - Westmoreland, Kans.
    - Associated Press
      - Miscellaneous
      - Stories
    - Book reviews
    - Congressional Record
    - Consolidated Press
    - English articles, 1934
    - English and Italian articles
    - Evening Eagle (Box C105)
    - German articles
    - Italy
    - Jewish Tribune, selective immigration
    - McClure Newspaper Syndicate
    - Methodist article, Christian Advocate
    - Miscellaneous
      - General, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box C106)
      - Biographical
      - Cuts of Henry J. Allen
      - Favorable comment
      - News
      - Personal
      - Requests for publication
      - Unfavorable comment
    - New York Times
    - Press releases
      - 1929
      - 1930
    - Putnam's
    - Special publications (Box C107)
    - Topeka State Journal
    - Congratulatory letters
      - Editorials
    - United Press International
    - Wichita Beacon
    - Willebrandt, Mabel Walker, articles, prohibition, 1929
  - Speech Material (Box C108-C112)
    Speech material.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
    - Allen, Henry A., speeches (Box C108)
    - Communism
    - Constitution, U.S.
    - Democratic Party
    - Farm tenancy
    - Finance
    - Foreign trade
    - Government, miscellaneous (Box C109)
    - Government reorganization
    - London treaty
    - Miscellaneous, (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box C110)
    - Pension legislation
    - Prohibition
    - Republican National Committee
    - Republican Party
    - Republican platform
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
    - Social Security (Box C111)
    - Speakers bureaus
    - Speaking file
    - Supreme Court
    - Tariff (Box C112)
    - War debts
    - Wichita, Kans., water matter
  - Invitations (Box C113-C117)
    Invitations to events.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of organization or forum.
    - Appointments and invitations (Box C113)
    - Chamber of Commerce, 1935
    - Clubs, (2 folders)
    - Debates
    - Editorial, (2 folders)
    - Engagements and invitations (Box C114)
    - Fraternal, (2 folders)
    - Invitations to speakers
    - Miscellaneous, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box C115)
    - Miscellaneous organizations, (2 folders) (Box C116)
    - Personal appointments
    - Political invitations, (3 folders)
    - Radio, (2 folders)
    - Religious, (3 folders)
    - Schools, (3 folders) (Box C117)
    - Social invitations, (6 folders)
    - Speaking engagements
    - Washington Bicentennial
    - Women's organizations, (3 folders)
  - Miscellaneous (Box C118-C137)
    Correspondence, reports, speeches and writings, clippings, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of person, subject, organization, or type of material.
    - Agriculture (Box C118)
    - Allen, Henry J., accident
    - American Society of Newspaper Editors
    - Apartments
    - Applications
    - Appointment to Senate
    - Appointments, miscellaneous
      - Newspapers, (2 folders)
      - Planned selling (Box C119)
      - Publicity, oil
      - Senator Allen's office
      - Students, (3 folders)
      - Unemployment, (2 folders)
      - White House
    - Autographs, (3 folders)
    - Beer
    - Birthday letters
    - Birthday parties
    - Books received, (2 folders)
    - Books received and sent
    - Civilian Conservation Corps camps
    - Candidates, 1938
    - Central National Bank, Topeka, Kans.
    - Chicago World Fair, Chicago, Ill.
    - Child labor
    - Citizens Reconstruction Organization
    - Citizenship
    - Civil Service
    - Clark, George Rogers, celebration
    - Combine
    - Comments on Allen's speeches, (6 folders) (Box C120)
    - Community Chest
    - Comstock merger
    - Confidential file, voting record
    - Congratulatory letters, Apr. 1929
      - A-C, (3 folders)
      - D-R, (14 folders) (Box C121)
      - S-Z, (6 folders) (Box C122)
    - Congratulatory letters, Aug. 1930
    - Congressional Record
    - Constitution
    - Contributions (Box C123)
      - Baker University, Baldwin, Kans.
      - Bethany College, Lindsborg, Kans.
      - Boy Scouts of America
      - College of Emporia, Emporia, Kans.
      - Federal Council of Churches
      - First Methodist Episcopal Church, (4 folders)
      - Hekim, Keghovhi
      - Highland College, Highland, Kana.
      - Isely, Merrill N.
      - Kansas City Council of Clubs, Kansas City, Kans.
      - Kansas Council of Religious Education
      - Kansas Diamond Jubilee
      - Kansas League of Women Voters
      - Kansas Society for Crippled Children
      - Kansas Wesleyan University, Salina, Kans.
      - Miscellaneous
      - National Illiteracy Committee (Box C124)
      - National Kindergarten Association
      - Ottawa University, Ottawa, Kans.
      - Salvation Army
      - Southwestern College, Winfield, Kans.
      - Sprague Foundation
      - Unemployed Trading Post
      - University of Kansas, Lawrence, Kans.
      - Wesley Hospital Building Fund, Wichita, Kans.
      - Wesley Methodist Church, Wichita, Kans.
      - Wichita Community Chest, Wichita, Kans.
      - Wichita Home for the Aged, Wichita, Kans.
      - Wichita University, Flo Brown Memorial Laboratory
      - YMCA, Wichita, Kans.
      - YMC. College
      - YMCA
    - Council of Personnel Administration
    - Courtesy cards
    - Debenture
    - Dehner case
    - Depression, (2 folders)
    - Engagements closed
    - Engagements suspended
    - England, correspondence (Box C125)
    - English Speaking Union, (2 folders)
    - Europe
    - Favorable comment
    - Gas tax exemption
    - German situation
    - Gifts received, (2 folders)
    - Gold Star mothers
    - Golden wedding letters
    - Grain grading
    - Harvard Advertising Awards, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass. (Box C126)
    - Hoover, Herbert
    - Housing
    - Illiteracy Crusade
    - Immigration
    - Introductions
    - Introductions to president
    - Italy
    - Kansas Chamber of Commerce Survey Fund
    - Katz Advertising Agency, (2 folders)
    - Kimberley-Clark Co.
    - Kiwanis, (2 folders) (Box C127)
    - Ku Klux Klan
    - Labor
    - Law suits
    - League of Nations
    - Legislation
    - Letters of introduction, (2 folders)
    - Letters of recommendation, (3 folders)
    - Letters of sympathy
    - Letters prior to appointment
    - Lindley Memorial, Lawrence, Kans.
    - Loans
    - Lobbying
    - Mexico (Box C128)
      - Correspondence
      - Hinshaw, David
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous (Box C129)
      - McHenry, Myra
      - Memberships
      - Minnesota editors
    - Miscellaneous organizations
    - Money matters
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews
    - National military homes
    - Nebraska-Kansas (Box C130)
    - New York World's Fair, New York, N.Y.
    - Newspapers
    - Newspaper inquiries
    - Newspaper matters, (2 folders)
    - Newspaper prospects
    - Nobel Peace Prize
    - Norris (Mrs. George) Fund
    - Old age pensions
    - Pamphlets (Box C131)
    - Pan-American Conference
      - Articles
      - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Personal
      - American Foundation
      - Baker University, Baldwin, Kans.
      - Chauffeur
      - Christmas lists, (2 folders)
      - Clubs (Box C132)
      - Committee memberships
        - American Hellenic Committee
        - American League of Good Will
        - Bok Memorial Committee
        - Citizens Committee of 1000
        - Colonial Society of America
        - Educational Publicity, World Peace
        - Methodist Brotherhood Men's Work Committee
        - Miscellaneous
        - National Advisory Committee on Illiteracy
        - National Lincoln League
        - Pioneer Women's Memorial Association
        - Puerto Rico Child Health Committee
        - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation
        - U.S. Civil Legion
        - World Peace Commission
      - Floating University, New York, N.Y.
      - General correspondence
      - Golden Rule Foundation
      - Miscellaneous
      - Memberships (Box C133)
      - Mrs. Allen's correspondence
      - Photographs
      - University Travel Association
    - Philippine Islands
    - Political
    - Prohibition publicity
    - Prosperity suggestions
    - Publicity
    - Pulitzer jury
    - Radio
    - Railroads
    - Real estate (Box C134)
    - Religious
    - Republican National Committee
      - Miscellaneous, A-Z, 1928
      - Appointments
      - Information
      - Miscellaneous (Box C135)
    - Roosevelt Memorial Association
    - Russia, correspondence
      - 1933
      - 1934
    - Russia and Germany
    - School (Box C136)
    - Secretarial applications
    - Short selling
    - Sunday movies
    - Tariff
    - Tariff, oil
    - Taxes
    - Technocracy
    - Thermic syphons
    - Time
    - Unemployment insurance, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, Allen articles from Europe
      - Miscellaneous
    - Unemployment relief
    - University Travel Association
    - U.S. Chamber of Commerce
    - Vail Jewelry Co.
    - Virgin Islands
    - War debts
    - War prohibition
    - Washington (George) Bicentennial
    - Water shortages
    - Waterways (Box C137)
    - Western Union
    - Wheat
    - Wheat consumption publicity
    - White House, (2 folders)
      - Jeslin, Theodore
      - Newton, Walter H.
      - Richey, Lawrence
    - Wichita Chamber of Commerce, Wichita, Kans.
    - Wichita University, Wichita, Kans.
    - World Peace Commission
    - Women's organizations